PROMISE K. MTHUNZI	Email:	mthunzipromise8@gmail.com
Box 20, Mponela, Dowa	Mobile:	0884781046 / 0998794874

### PERSONAL PROFILE

Agriculture Economics Student at LUANAR. prior to my current education, I worked as an Agriculture research and extension officer and hold different enumerator positions, my great analytical skills coupled with my experience has equipped me with skills in data collection, analysis, creating appealing and informative visualizations and dashboards. I used my free time to learn how to clean, reshape databases and conduct deep analysis using excel and python. My education has toppled me how to conduct statistical procedures such as ANOVA, Linear and Logistic regression, Hypothesis testing and the basics of other statistical tools such as STATA and SPSS. I am a self-starter and I love learning new technologies, thus am open to opportunities which can expand my skills in data science.

# **EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATION**

BSc in Agriculture Economics- LUANAR	Undergraduate
Diploma in Agriculture – Mwimba College of Agriculture	2017
• Field Research Training- Institute of Public Opinion and Research(IPOR)	2023
MSCE – Dowa Secondary School	2013

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Monitoring and evaluation	Quantitative analysis	Python, R, STATA, SPSS
Community Mobilization	Data collection and recording	ODK, Interviewer, Survey CTO
Team work and Collaboration	Data Visualization	Excel and Google Sheets
Problem solving skills	Relational databases	Google maps, UTM maps.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

<b>Enumerator</b> – National Cercus of	National Statistics Office(NSO)	12 August 2024 – Present
Agriculture(NACA) Household Listing		

- SADC regional statistics capacity project in Malawi, aim is to strengthen institutional capacity of the nation to record, produce and disseminate high quality statistics while increasing regional harmonization and collaboration.
  - ✓ Listing households and collecting demographic data in Salima and Nkhotakota district
  - ✓ Mastered use of interviewer app, tracing and identifying households and structures using UTM maps..

<b>Enumerator</b> – Unified Beneficiary	Zomba District Council	15 Dec 2022 – 11 March 2023
Registry(UBR)		

- Malawi Government Social Protection Program, Frontier in household registration which helps in harmonization process for different social support programs
  - ✓ Survey administration
  - ✓ Assisted in data collection tasks by leading in community entry and organizing meetings with village leaders to conduct secondary sensitization and awareness.
  - ✓ Improved group performance by organizing evening meetings for reporting and planning.
  - ✓ Helped to address data collection challenges such as hostile communities and misunderstanding between other enumerators and respondents.
  - ✓ Survey administration.

Agriculture Research and	Farmer Service Unit-AGORA	2018 – 2023
Extension officer		

- A Farmer targeted project under Farmers World and AGORA, aimed at famers capacity building by educating them in soil nutrients and fertilizers, agronomy and providing field support as well as agriculture inputs loan packages.
  - ✓ Mobilized and facilitated development of farmer groups and Village savings Associations
  - ✓ Agronomic training by using group trainings, clinic sessions, demonstration plots and in-shop trainings.
  - ✓ Coordinate and managed fertilizer, inoculant research and demonstration plots in Maize, Beans, Groundnuts, Sweet potato, Soya and Cowpeas.
  - ✓ Conducted a variety of surveys and collecting time series data from registered famers.
  - ✓ Trained famers in financial literacy modules: Farming as business, Book-keeping, Cash flow management, budgeting, business planning and marketing.
  - ✓ Identified farmer eligible for agriculture loan inputs, collecting collateral, giving loan packages and ensuring famers observe loan repayment schedule.
  - ✓ Soil sampling and explain soil report results to famers.
  - ✓ Raised brand visibility of Agora, Famers world, Demeter and other partners products.
  - ✓ Collaborate with other stakeholders including government extension officers during Field days and Agriculture Marketing shows.

## **REFERENCES**

MR AUSTIN CHAUMA	MR FRANK LEMANI	MR CHIMWEMWE MAELE
NSO NACA Field Supervisor	ADC Zomba District Council	FSU South Team Manager
NSO, Zomba.	UBR Team Supervisor	Box 51142
	Box 123, Zomba	AGORA, LIMBE
Cell: +265 897 09 90 20	Cell: +265 9999 49 54 08	Cell: +265 999 28 86 70